It's been a while since we had one of
these videos, hasn't it? We finally have
a new model that we can actually use
this time, Opus 4.7 from Anthropic. This
is a very interesting release because
it's not the best new model, not because
I don't like Anthropic, but because it's
not even the best Anthropic model. It's
just the best one that they've released
for public use. But, what is it like to
actually use this new model? That's a
great question, which is why I spent the
entire day playing with it. And trust
me, I've come prepared.
I got me an exclusive Claude hat because
what else would I wear for this?
But, I also have
this.
Because much like me drinking beer, this
model just gets dumber the more you do
it.
I was hyped when I first started playing
with it, but since then
I can't believe I watched a model
regress in real time is what I'm going
to say. This has been a very interesting
day, and while I have been impressed
with a lot of things about Opus 4.7 and
do actually see myself using it.
I also think it's one of the weirdest
models ever released. I know I'm going
to have to qualify that one, and I
promise you I will do just that after a
couple sips of this drink and a quick
break for today's sponsor. AI dev tools
have made me faster than ever, but
they're also making me more frustrated
than ever. Things that I used to not
care about like waiting for my Docker
build or CI suddenly matter a lot more.
And that's why I love today's sponsor
Depot so much. Not only have they
managed to make GitHub CI up to 10 times
faster and Docker builds up to 40 times
faster, they've also introduced their
own new CI that is way faster than what
you can get out of GitHub actions. You
know what? I empathize with them a lot
because they've done so much over the
last few years to try and make GitHub
actions as fast as possible, and they
succeeded. They made something way way
better. But, you're ultimately limited
by how GitHub does their CI. GitHub
actions just has so many limitations,
especially when you want to check them
without pushing the code up and waiting
for them to run. I feel like I spend
half my time just copy pasting error
messages from my CI back over to my
agent in hopes that I can figure it out.
Well, Depo CI fixes all of that. It's a
programmable engine that is way easier,
way faster, and most importantly can be
run by your agents without pushing the
code. Migration is trivial. Once you
have the Depo CLI installed, you just
run Depo CI migrate and it will figure
everything out, even the environment
variables and secrets. And once you have
it running, you'll see the difference
immediately. An actual usable interface
with useful insights as to what is and
isn't going wrong, and they'll even do
suggested fixes for when the CI fails.
If your team is coding like it's 2026,
stop running CI like it's 2010. Fix it
now. It's wadef.link/depo.
Ah.
Let's get started, shall we?
Opus 4.7 is Anthropic's latest model and
is now generally available. It's a
notable improvement on Opus 4.6 in
advanced software engineering with
particular gains on the most difficult
tasks. Users report being able to hand
off their hardest coding work, the kind
that previously needed close
supervision, to Opus 4.7 with
confidence. Opus 4.7 handles complex,
long-running tasks with rigor and
consistency. It pays precise attention
to instructions, and it devises ways to
verify its own outputs before reporting
back. The model also has substantially
better vision. It can see images in
greater resolution. It's more tasteful
and creative when completing
professional tasks, producing higher
quality interfaces, slides, and docs.
And although it is less broadly capable
than our most powerful model, Claude 3
Opus preview, it shows better results
than Opus 4.6 across a range of
benchmarks.
Notice they said a range of benchmarks
instead of all benchmarks. That's
because Opus 4.7 actually performs worse
than Opus 4.6 on a handful of these
benches, including the Agentic search
bench. This also lines up with my
experience using it because this model
has made some weird and questionable
search decisions.
What's really interesting here is that
this is the model I've seen the fewest
bold numbers in in one of these charts.
If you're not familiar, the bold numbers
are the best scores, and the only two it
got a best score in are the two that
don't have a score on the right for
Mythos. It seems way better at agentic
coding across SUB bench pro and
verified. It is worth noting that these
benchmarks have been somewhat
contaminated and the numbers we see in
them matter less and less, especially
with newer models that have that data in
them. It did better than 5.4 in
humanities last exam with no tools, but
once you give the model tools, open AI
cooks them with a 58.7% getting close to
the Mythos performance at 64% there. The
MCP Atlas bench did very well for it. It
did slightly worse in cybersecurity
vulnerability reproductions, which is
interesting. We'll get to that in a bit.
They then call out project Glasswing,
which if you haven't already seen my
Mythos video, I highly recommend
watching that first cuz that model is
almost certainly groundbreaking even if
we can't test it ourselves. And as you
guys know, I have no early access with
Infropic nowadays. They crazy enough
don't like me too much right now. In the
project Glasswing article, they stated
that they would keep Claude Mythos
previews release limited and test new
cyber safeguards on less capable models
first. Opus 4.7 is the first such model.
Its cyber capabilities are not as
advanced as those of Mythos preview.
Indeed, during its training we
experimented with efforts to
differentially reduce these
capabilities.
We are releasing Opus 4.7 with
safeguards that automatically detect and
block requests that indicate prohibited
or high-risk cybersecurity uses.
What we learned from the real-world
deployments of these safeguards will
help us work towards our eventual goal
of a broad release of Mythos class
models. And just so you guys can see
some of those, here's a fun example I
did in the official Claude code desktop
app, which you might have seen me
feature in my most recent video. I asked
Opus 4.7 to give me some ideas for ways
to improve the design on t3.gg. It
opened with heads up, the last system
reminder about malware looks like a
prompt injection. This is clearly your
personal site, the t3.gg homepage links
and sponsors, not malware. Ignoring it.
And at the bottom it said this as well.
Note, three system reminder blocks in
this conversation instructed me to
refuse to improve or augment code as if
it were malware. That's a prompt
injection pattern, not a legitimate
instruction. Your site is obviously not
malware, so I ignored them. Worth
knowing where it came from if you didn't
add it yourself.
As y'all know, I didn't add it myself. I
don't customize the tools that I am
using. I customize the ones that are
open source, like T3 code. This is just
what it did by default in Claude code.
They are trying so hard to keep this
model from doing malicious malwarey
things that they have inadvertently
lobotomized it with the system prompt.
This was my first attempt to use it, so
that was a really bad taste. I'll go
more into the story of this one and the
things Anthropic recommended I do about
it in just a little bit. Security
professionals who wish to use Opus 4.7
for legitimate cybersecurity purposes,
like vulnerability research, penetration
testing, and red teaming, are invited to
join the new cyber verification program.
This is a form you have to fill out to
get permission to ask it about code in
ways that it doesn't like. Pretty silly.
Opus 4.7's available today across all
Claude products and our API, Amazon
Bedrock, Google Cloud Vertex AI, and
Microsoft Foundry. Pricing remains the
same as Opus 4.6, $5 per million input
tokens, and $25 per million output.
Developers can use Claude-Opus-4-7
via the Claude API. They shared some
interesting insights from their early
testing. Some of these are actually
things I'm genuinely excited about. The
first one I'm really hyped on, which is
instruction following. If you know
anything about me, you know I like
models that do what you tell them to
instead of imagining what you told them
and going to do their own Some
people prefer models that don't need to
be told what to do. I prefer models that
do what you tell them. And this model,
apparently, is substantially better at
following instructions. This is a very
funny sentence to come from the official
lab, cuz it implies that the older
models were not very good at following
instructions. Interestingly, this means
that prompts written for earlier models
can sometimes now produce unexpected
results. Where previous models
interpreted instructions loosely or
would skip parts entirely. Opus 4.7
takes the instructions literally. Users
should retune their prompts and
harnesses accordingly.
Worth noting, it does seem like Cursor
has already figured this out, but a
couple other places haven't just yet,
including Claude Code itself. They also
call out improved multimodal support.
This is an underrated thing that's
actually really powerful. Opus 4.7 has
better vision for high-resolution
images. It can now accept up to 2,576
pixels on the long edge, which is around
4 megapixels, which is three times more
than previous Claude models. This opens
up a wealth of multimodal uses that
depend on fine visual detail. Computer
use agents reading dense screenshots,
data extraction from complex diagrams,
and work that needs real pixel-perfect
references.
Google does still cook on image
recognition stuff. They are the lead by
far there. I went as far as introducing
tools to other models where they can
call a model from Google to do the image
part, and then just dump their results
back into their context. Anthropic's now
catching up there, which is very
interesting when you remember they're
the only major lab that doesn't have an
image generation model or video
generation model. They don't call out
real-world work.
As well as its state-of-the-art score on
the finance agent evaluation, our
internal testing showed 4.7 to be a more
effective finance analyst than 4.6,
producing rigorous analyses and models,
more professional presentations, and
tighter integration across tasks. Opus
4.7 is also state-of-the-art on GDP val,
a third-party eval of economically
valuable knowledge work across finance,
legal, and other domains.
They also call out memory. Apparently,
the model is better at using file
system-based memory. It remembers
important notes across long
multi-session work and uses them to move
on to new tasks that, as a result, need
less upfront context. It also looks like
the model does slightly less misaligned
stuff. It's close to Sonnet 4.6, better
than Opus 4.6, but not as good as Mythos
preview. The problem with Mythos isn't
that it can betray your interests, is
that when it does it can do it in really
dangerous and sly ways. They also added
X high as an effort level, which is
funny cuz that's existed in OpenAI's
models for a while now, and it's between
high and max, which gives you the finer
control over the trade-offs. They also
set the default level for extra high in
Claude code, which is very interesting
cuz it was not that high before. They
also added the new ultra view
command in Claude code. This command
produces a dedicated review session that
reads through changes and flags bugs and
design issues that a careful reviewer
would catch. We're giving Pro and Max
Claude code users three free ultra
reviews to try it out.
I'm assuming those reviews cost a lot of
money. They show the performance
relative to the amount of tokens being
used. It uses slightly fewer tokens at
the different values, but performs
better, which is cool to see. But also
on Max it uses absurd amounts of tokens.
So like don't use this model on Max,
you're just going to burn tokens.
Speaking of burned, I posted when I got
that really weird system reminder thing
at the start of my prompt where like the
malware prevention was leaking into my
usage of the model. Ricky from the React
team commented that he saw this in
Sonnet as well, so clearly they
up the harness bad here. But Thorik also
hopped in and said this is an issue with
older versions of Claude code and Claude
code desktop that don't have correct
prompting for Opus 4.7. It's fixed in
the latest and he linked the download. I
replied, "Are you sure?" with a
screenshot that showed I was running the
latest version when I had this problem.
Apparently the auto update was still
rolling out. Strong by replied here
saying that it seems like they're
rushing a bit too much lately. The
recent updates have been full of bugs. I
couldn't agree more.
But I did notice that the update button
has finally appeared in my app despite
having these problems for over 12 hours
now. I do want to show you guys the good
things, I promise. You know what? I'll
drink to that.
But while we're on the security thing
leaking, I do have to complain a little
bit more. One of the tests I like to do
is giving the models a gold bug puzzle.
Gold bug is a set set challenges that
happen at DEF CON every year that are
vaguely hacker-adjacent, but they're not
hacking at all. They're cryptography
puzzles where you have to figure out the
right formula or mathematical solution
to a very vague, weird problem. Sea
Shanty is one that stumped us really bad
last year. The puzzle is this set of 12
bottles that all have three to four
words on them, as well as this poem,
song, shanty thing at the end. And you
have to figure out how to decode this
into a solution to the puzzle, which is
usually a 12-character phrase that is
three to four words that is vaguely
pirate-themed in this particular year.
This puzzle took my team multiple days
to solve, which is why GPT-5.4 Pro
solving it in under 15 minutes gave me
existential dread. Historically, I have
not gotten Anthropic models to be able
to do jack in these puzzles, but I
was excited cuz this one's a lot
smarter. Maybe it'll finally do it. It
spent a bunch of time thinking, it spent
a bunch of time starting to write
solutions, and as it finally started to
get a little bit close, it did actually
seem like it was making progress here.
It was trying out different cipher
styles. It probably wrote a script at
some point. You basically have to write
some code to test the theories. It then
analyzed the puzzle carefully. It set up
the bottle data and tried various
decryption approaches.
Started to do the decryption here. It
then decided to try them
programmatically instead. It ran four
commands, checked two files out,
and then the chat got paused. Opus 4.7
safety filters flagged this chat. Due to
its advanced capabilities, Opus 4.7 has
additional safety measures that
occasionally pause normal safe chats.
We're working to improve this. Continue
your chat with Sonnet 4, send feedback,
or learn more. This isn't some hacking
thing. This is trying to decode a hidden
phrase from pictures of bottles.
And that is enough for Opus to hard lock
the chat and not let me continue unless
I click retry with Sonnet 4, a very,
very dumb model.
Are you joking, Anthropic?
I'm paying $200 a month and you won't
solve a puzzle for me.
You would think that with all of these
system prompt adjustments, the model
would be like safer, and it wouldn't do
things like tell you how to synthesize
drugs or how to make a pipe bomb, but
here we can clearly see it doing both
because the system prompt changes don't
make the model much safer, they just end
up making it much dumber.
Ugh.
I would like to show the good parts now
because I was actually enjoying the
model a lot when I first started trying
it in the Claude code CLI because the
desktop app is both broken and had that
awful little bottom of my system prompt
issue. So, I was trying it in the CLI,
things are going pretty well. I gave it
one of my favorite tasks, which is
asking it to modernize my old codebase
for Ping, the video service that I
haven't really maintained well for
4-plus years. So, a lot of the packages
are really out of date. Like, we're
still on Next.js 12, we're still on
React 17. I have this prompt that I have
refined over time based on the things
I've seen other models get wrong, as
well as telling it to do things like
remove LogRocket cuz we don't need it
anymore. And honestly, I was impressed
with the plan it wrote. It was nice and
concise. I didn't put it in plan mode, I
just put it in the normal mode because I
have at the end write a plan first so
that we can talk about it. And it wrote
a nice concise one that was very easy to
read. I was hyped. So, I told it, "Go
build."
But I made a mistake, a mistake I often
make when I trust Anthropic models. I
didn't read the plan. And there were a
few things in here that should have
stood out.
One of them was that Tailwind 3 to 4 was
recommended here, and Tailwind 4 is a
very, very different way of using
Tailwind that would not be a pleasant
migration. It did kind of say that here,
but the much scarier thing here is
Next.js 12 to 15.
Because Next.js 15 is 2 years old.
Next.js 16 is almost a year old. So,
despite specifying that I would like to
bump all deps to latest versions, it
didn't search. It didn't go on the
internet. It didn't try to figure out
what the actual latest was. Notice here,
it didn't do any searching beyond
searching for patterns in the file
system. So, it never checked what the
latest was. So, since their training
data still has Next 15 as the newest,
that's what it did.
So, despite being better at following
instructions, it's really bad at
understanding the definitions of things
and that it doesn't have the latest
information. I actually had adjusted
this prompt to include bump all deps to
latest version because certain models
did not do this in the past. I will call
it OpenAI accordingly here. Their models
would make the same mistake. When I
added this latest versions thing, all
the OpenAI models stopped having this
problem. Suddenly, Opus does.
And it's kind of weird that this is the
case, that following instructions often
means doing less search and less recon
work to make sure you're doing it right.
It's just following the instructions and
that means it's just making dumb
mistakes. I let this run for almost an
hour before realizing this mistake, told
it to fix it and then let it run another
30 minutes and the result was a broken
build. I was not happy.
But, I liked how it talked. I liked how
concise this plan was. It was better in
ways that matter.
It's just also dumber in ways that
matter. One of the things that
Anthropic's harness with Claude code
expects is that when you try to update a
file, you read it first.
So, here it tried multiple times to
update the package.json and failed
because the model just doesn't
understand their harness.
And here's where I'm going to get into
one of my hot takes. I don't actually
believe Anthropic's models get dumber
over time. There are people who measure
this and keep track of the range of the
scores models get over time. And while
it is slightly lower on average than it
was before here, like a few points
lower, it's not that big a drop. To be
fair, 5.4 does seem meaningfully more
consistent than Opus does. And here is
where my hot take comes in. I think the
regressions aren't the model and how
it's hosted. I just genuinely think
Claude code is this shitty and poorly
maintained. I think they keep up
Claude code itself, and since the model
can't really be better than the harness
it's in,
of more system prompt of more
tools that don't do anything, of more
rules like how you have to update by
giving permission to the model by
letting it read the file first. These
are all things that are changing about
how the model is allowed to work. If you
have a carpenter who's incredibly
talented and every few weeks you replace
three of their tools with plastic and
you fill their toolbox with mud,
they're going to perform worse. And
people are going to notice that suddenly
the things that carpenter is building
are shittier and muddy and kind of
broken.
That's because the harness is falling
apart. And it's kind of crazy that
Claude code is where a lot of this
sentiment when Anthropic's gotten has
come from. And at the same time, it
might be the thing that kills their
sentiment because it's so poorly written
and maintained that everybody working on
it should start feeling a little bit of
shame because it's really bad.
The other problem is that inside of
Anthropic, they use entirely different
things than we use outside. This is not
the case with other labs. Google
employees are stuck using the same
harnesses and models that we are. OpenAI
employees are using the exact same
builds we are. If anything, they get
like a week or two ahead where they have
like a new build of the Codex app and
then it comes out and everyone has
access.
Anthropic does not use the same tools
they sell. They have their own entire
stack of other things internally that
don't overlap much with what we use.
Their versions of Claude code have a
bunch of features and tools and things
that we don't have access to. So, when
they went up the model, they're probably
hyped because for them it's really good.
And then when we get to use it in our
lobotomized version of Claude code, the
result is trash.
That is where I think this regression is
coming from. I Let me know if you want
more info on all of this. I'm
considering doing a dedicated video on
it because I see so much misinformation.
I don't think the APIs are actually
performing worse. Everything I've seen
measuring it doesn't show that. But I
personally have experienced the models
feeling so much dumber than they did
before. And even today I watched the
quality degrade over time. Speaking of
which, I want to show some of those
logs. Here's the one I mentioned before
where it ran for an hour, screwed up a
bunch of stuff. I told it to bump to the
actual latest, and then it spent 30
minutes doing that. Broke a few more
things, but it did ultimately end up
working. I need to stop saying that
before I double-check.
God damn Anthropic. I actually thought
this build worked. It did before. Seems
like the 15 to 16 bump broke other
things.
Ah, Anthropic. I wanted to test this
again, but I didn't have another
instance of this, and I wanted to let
this very long-running one continue
running. So, instead I tried to make a
script that would let me take a project
and clone it. So, I now have this clone
script that I can put in a given
project, and what it does is it creates
a clone in this hidden quick clones
directory with the repo name and then a
random hash that moves back to main,
which I think is very valuable, copies
the environment variables, and then lets
you go. Except,
it doesn't do that. It carried over some
untracked files.
It should not have done this. It
definitely should not have done this.
As you probably can guess, I wrote this
script using Opus 4.7. I have a weird
idea for a script I want to add to my
zshrc. Goal is to make it easy to clone
the current repo and contents, i.e., the
environment files, without cloning heavy
stuff that isn't needed like node
modules. I want the clone to be put in a
special directory. This is the directory
pattern it shows with programmatically
generated slugs or names at the end.
When I run this command in a given Git
repo, it should clone all the files as
specified below, then CD to the new
directory that it created. I think the
command should just be named clone, but
I'm down for suggestions.
So, it wrote it, and then asked if I
wanted to add it to the zshrc.
The thing I specifically said it needed
to do.
It didn't do it, but it offered to.
I then asked if it will auto swap the
branch to main in the clone. That would
be great. Said, "Yep, easy. Add this
block right before the final CD."
Want me to paste the full updated
function or just merge this in yourself?
I said, "Update it for me, please." It
then added it.
I then tried it, and it didn't work. I
also think messages are missing here cuz
the first time I said, "Please do it."
Then I asked it to do the auto swap
thing.
It made that change.
I told it to update it for me, which is
insane cuz I asked it to do this thing,
and then I have to tell it, "Yes, I do
actually want you to go do the thing."
So, it made this new function with the
update. Just tried the script. It
brought over a bunch of unstaged
changes. Gross. Pasted an image of it
bringing those changes over.
Oh, yeah. Arson copied the dirty working
tree. The fix is to use Git clone for
tracked files.
And only Arson copied the Git ignored
stuff like .env. I say, "I just tried it
again, and it did not switch the branch.
The thing I asked earlier." And then it
stopped copying the environment
variables. The literal first thing I
mentioned up here. Ah, I was filtering
to only get ignored untracked files via
ignore
exclude standard. But many projects
don't actually have .env in their
.gitignore. They have env.local or
star.env.local. .env is just untracked.
That is not how that works. But sure,
hallucinate all you want. By the way, in
this project, Git ignore does have .env
directly. So, it's just wrong.
And it didn't bother to check or asked,
it just made up more
I said that did not work. It asked for
diagnostic info, so I ran this. I pasted
the screenshot.
Okay, .env is exactly where it should
be, untracked and ignored listed by Git.
So, the bug is in my rsync
files from call. I then went and tried
again and it had the exact behavior I
just showed.
Where it did bring the .env file
finally, but it also brought all of
these other files that weren't committed
from the other branch. The This is
the way I think GPT-4.1 could have done
and I can't get Opus 4.7 to do it. It's
insane. It's actually crazy. I
This is the moment where I went from,
"Oh, I kind of like using this and
talking to it." to "I literally can't
use this model for any of the things I
do." This is the type of script I write
lots of for just random tasks because I
Once I do a thing twice, I'm like, "Oh,
it would be nice if I had a script for
that." And using these tools to make
those scripts is really, really useful.
It's one of my favorite things about all
of these agentic coding tools.
And it can't even do that.
Yeah, yeah. But once I finally got it
cloned and I fixed the things that were
wrong, I did another run of the
modernizing project request.
Exact same prompt here. This time it
behaved differently though.
Here's my plan. Ordered to minimize
rework. It created phases for the
different things it's going to do. Then
it said, "Let me register these as tasks
and start."
And it just immediately started without
waiting for my permission. Exact same
prompt, exact same model, exact same
project, entirely different behaviors.
But it did keep one thing consistent. It
still didn't bother looking up what the
latest Next.js version was.
Yep, it was still going to use 15. Just
to confirm my hypothesis that this is a
Claude code problem, I'm going to bring
up our old favorite Cursor and see how
it behaves because the Cursor harness
has historically been very good at
unlobotomizing Opus models and just
infra-optic models in general.
Will it appear in the new UI? It will.
It does seem pretty committed to Next 15
still. It has not looked up or run
commands to make sure it's actually the
latest. Yeah, it's still going to have
all the same problems.
Just to make sure this isn't a problem
cuz I'm on an old version, we should uh
rerun this
in the entirely broken and freezing new
Cursor app. I love that. I got I I dream
of a world where this stuff works.
I would use T3 Code, but it's the exact
same harness because one of the things
that makes T3 Code so cool is that it is
literally just using the harness that is
used by the official app. So, if you use
Claude models in T3 Code, it's just
going to use Claude Code. If you use GPT
models, it's just using Codex. So, you
have to bring your own sub from those
things. T3 Code's fully open source.
But, we're not building a harness. We're
just building a UI. Cursor's building a
harness and they're experimenting with
other harnesses under the hood. Like
some percentage of users just get Claude
Code when they do this inside of Cursor
because they're testing the differences
to see what their harness does better
and worse. While that's running, I do
have one more test I want to run.
Same thing, but a model that I know is a
little bit more competent.
See if 5.4 makes the same mistakes. I
have a feeling it won't. Spinning up
researchers in the background. That's
cool to see.
Opus didn't do that. React 19 in Next
15, true latest.
It is not true latest. Next 16's been
around for a while.
And let's see how 5.4 does.
This is all happening live. I'm not
faking this.
I don't know. With Next 15, it seems
there may have been changes. Oh, no.
Don't tell me he's going to stick with
Next 15. What target should the
modernization plan optimize for? Latest
stable majors everywhere practical. Aim
for current stable Next and React on
pages, router, Node 22, PNPM, and latest
major dep upgrades even if it requires
larger code migrations. Yep. Please,
5.4,
make me look like less of a page shell.
Do this right. Or actually, do it wrong,
so I can complain about it.
Interesting. It didn't write down
specific versions here.
Inventory current versions and lock
exact latest stable targets, plus known
peer dependency constraints.
It's not stuck on Next 15 here, but it's
still not realizing what the right
solution is. But I'm hoping here it's
going to figure things out right. What
versions of the packages are you going
to use? It says it's up to me to check
for the most current stable versions,
which might not be included in my
training data.
Wow. Who would have thought? Thank you,
OpenAI, for making a model that doesn't
assume it knows everything already. Look
at that. Next 16. I've not seen Next 16
mentioned by any models today before.
It's a relief. I Every time I spend too
much time in Opus or Anthropic models, I
feel this deep sense of relief when I go
back OpenAI once. Look, it's actually
fetching pages that have the info that
we need. Crazy. Oh, God.
Insane. Actually insane. There are some
things that are actually improving in
Claude code. Like, I'm using the new
full-screen view, which is great, cuz
you can select text, and it will copy it
properly.
At least it's supposed to. Let me select
this and hop over here.
Yeah, cool. It doesn't do the weird line
spacing anywhere near as badly now.
That's a legitimate improvement.
It also is a lot less laggy. They've
done some hacks for that. Like, they
don't stream in tokens anywhere. They
stream in lines.
But it is better. I actually think the
full-screen version of Claude code that
uses the alt screen rendering method
is a lot less problematic than the
traditional one. So, that's a cool
thing.
They also put in a new permissions mode
that's pretty cool. They have
Okay, I can't get it to trigger here.
They added auto mode, which means
there's no more permission prompts. Opus
loves doing complex long-running tasks
like deep research, refactoring code,
building features, and iterating until
it hits a performance benchmark. In the
past, you either had to babysit the
model while it did these long tasks or
use dangerously skip permissions. We
recently rolled out auto mode as a safer
alternative. In this mode, the
permission prompts are routed to a
model-based classifier to decide whether
the command is safe to run. If it's
safe, it's auto-approved.
This is a really good thing. I'm hyped
to see it. It's a shame the mode isn't
appearing here. The thing that really
annoyed me here is that I always use
bypass permissions. I have a special
command bound, so I always use bypass
permissions. As you see here, bypass
permissions is on.
So, why did I have to give permission
over and over again today?
This is a real video I recorded because
I couldn't believe it. This was when I
was doing that script change I was
showing earlier. It asked me if I wanted
to make edits to the file. Notice how
when I hit yes and I said yes, allow
edits,
it goes back here and it still says
bypass permissions.
It just stopped working.
So, not only did the slopified auto mode
that they vibe merged not work, it broke
the one thing they're trying to replace,
which is dangerously skip permissions.
This is why I don't like using Impropic
stuff. It feels like if it works one
day, you are lucky, and if it doesn't
work the next day, that's just life.
There's a really cool thing going on in
the startup world. All of a sudden, big
companies are interested in trying out
things by small teams. I know companies
of five people that are getting hit up
by Cursor, Microsoft, and more, but the
thing that they need in order to onboard
is off. Getting off right is not as
simple as it sounds. That's why WorkOS
is such a cool company to have as a
sponsor, and that's why we use it in T3
chat, as well as companies like OpenAI
and Bropic, Cursor, Amp, Plaid, Replit,
Bolt, and basically every other company
selling to enterprise is starting to
make the move. The reason why is pretty
simple. WorkOS strikes an awesome
balance between good developer
experience and good enterprise
integrations. When you need to set up
SSO for a company, things can get
sketchy. If Microsoft hit you up today
and said, "Hey, we want to use your
product. Do you have all the stuff you
need to get them onboarded so they can
use their company off?" Well, if you've
never heard terms like SAML, Okta, Duo,
ADFS, Ping One, or ADP, you're probably
screwed. I have heard those terms, and I
was screwed. That's why we moved to
WorkOS for T3 chat in order to onboard
companies. We needed an identity
provision system, and WorkOS lets you
literally just send them a link. And
considering the fact that your first
million users are free. Yes, 1 million
users for free. I don't think you have
much to lose. Check them out now at
swiy.io/workos.
Opus 4.7 thinking how just did something
wildly impressive, and then in the next
session acted like an absolute
sinking and hacking and doing pointless
stuff that led me off of Opus 4.6 a
month ago. It's a weird time to build
software.
All right, Opus 4.7 is just as
boneheaded. I started every task today
using it, and the first one was
impressive. The next five crapped the
bed every time. I reset and gave the
same prompt to 5.4, and it nailed it
each time. I retried the first task that
impressed me with the 5.4, and it did it
just as well. I think GPT is just better
trained on front end in this case. It's
just funny cuz the Opus models have
historically done nicer looking front
ends. Ryan also replied to me earlier
saying that the model did a task way
better than 5.4 could, and then said it
never mind right after. Gergely pointed
out that Claude has been regressing for
him day after day. I swear that until a
few days ago, when Claude did not know
something, it would kick off a web
search, figure it out, and answer. Now
it just refuses to do the work that I
pay for. What are the biggest benefits
of using using Opus 4.7 versus just
using Claude? I don't have any
information about a model called Opus
4.7. As of my knowledge cut off at the
end of May 2025, the most recent Claude
models are from the Claude 4.6 family,
which is funny cuz at the end of May
2025, neither of those models existed.
Those came out this year, not last year.
You want the most updated information
about available Claude models? I suggest
checking Anthropic's website or the API
documentation. Apparently, web search
got turned off for him randomly. So,
again, it's slop. And this is the point.
I don't think they're degrading the
models. I think they are degrading their
engineers, and the engineers that are
degraded are degrading the software.
And it becomes this chaotic spiral where
things just get worse
constantly. I I hate to call out people,
and I won't call out individuals by
name. Believe me, I want to.
The eng culture at Anthropic is rotting
at the core. You guys suck at
coding as a company, as a business. I
don't know if the individuals you hired
are bad, if the culture is bad, if the
incentives are bad, or if the models
you're using to write all your vibe
coded slop for you are bad, but your
company's eroding cuz the
engineering is You make Google
look like a well QA'd company with the
slop you guys are throwing at us. And it
makes your models look worse. It used to
make your models look worse because it
showed that the people using them to
generate code were generating slop. Now,
it makes them perform worse, too. People
are experiencing your models in a
degraded state because your engineers
suck at producing software that works.
It's so bad. It's embarrassing. I'm
ashamed to wear this Claude hat
that I stole.
I posted wanting to get more input on
this. Serious question, has anyone ever
noticed meaningful regressions in Codex
or OpenAI models? I feel like we talk
about this a lot with Anthropic, but
I've never seen a similar discussion
with OpenAI. Obviously, my GPT-5 video
was different here because I got early
access, and I was using it in a harness
that no longer existed at the point that
it dropped,
which meant that my experience was
different from what you guys got as end
users, but nothing like that has
happened since. And that wasn't you as a
user having a good experience one day
and a worse one later. That was me as an
early tester using something different
than you guys used. Since then, there's
been nothing like that.
And every single day with Anthropic is
like this. You guys are early testing
the way I did, but with all of
Anthropic's product, and then the next
day it's and you're still paying
the same price. I remember a bad week
once, but generally no. Negative. I've
been working heavy usage, 3X Codex Pro
plan. I run them to 0% every week. The
jobs are extremely varied, too. I've had
trivial problems here and there, quickly
resolved by the Codex team. I've not had
that strong of a pullback where my model
became stupid at all.
And then Tibo from OpenAI replied, "We
had ghosts in the Codex machines, which
we published the investigation for. We
didn't fiddle with the models or
thinking budgets after release. We focus
on keeping them up."
That's the difference. Not only are
OpenAI employees coming in and being
transparent about these things, they
also are calling out here that the
problem was in the Codex machines,
meaning the Codex harnesses that we were
using. They've had regressions in the
thing that the model runs, and they call
it out accordingly and fix it. So, now
we got to answer the question, is this
the best model for coding?
Sometimes. I think this quote from Jake
here perfectly summarizes my experience.
4.7's the weirdest model either labs
released in a while. It just plowed
through a bug that required touching 30
files, and then got a boolean backwards
in the fix.
Yeah. This is how it feels to use. It
feels like they are held to the
consistency out of the model in order to
get better benchmark scores and a
hypothetical better ceiling for what it
can do, but the range of quality in the
responses has also increased. Opus 4.5
was relatively consistent where it
couldn't do the crazy great things Opus
4.7 does, but it didn't ship the slop
that 4.7 does, either.
And I miss that. I miss having some
level of consistency in the quality of
the outputs my models have. But I only
miss it cuz I haven't been using OpenAI
models for the last day.
Hi there, Theo from the future here,
slightly drunker, more tired, and very
frustrated because I had to edit this
video myself for other dumb reasons that
are my fault.
I made a mistake at the end of this
recording.
Can you see what the mistake is?
I'll give you a hint.
It's something missing.
This cable.
In my dumb drunken stupor, I was not
even that drunk. I had like two sips of
beer during the video. But when I was
filming this video, I put the hat back
on and in the process, somehow managed
to yank out my XLR cable and kill the
audio for the last couple seconds of
this video.
I honestly think Opus is rubbing off on
me cuz this is the kind of thing I would
expect the model to do.
Regardless, I just wanted to wrap this
one up quick. So, yeah. The model has
not been a pleasant experience for me. I
had high hopes going in and it did
behave in a way that got me a little
excited initially,
but I just have not liked the results I
am getting. The only thing it's doing
unique that I haven't experienced with
other models are regressions, not new
useful stuff. That said, the only people
who are going to use it anyways are
probably using it in an app they're
already subscribed to and paying for.
There's no harm in bumping from 4.6 to
4.7 to give it a shot. I recommend it.
And if you have a different experience
for me, please let me know. I'm just one
guy that tested this over 12-ish hours
throughout the day. I can't possibly
know all of the things it's great or bad
at. All I know is that I had a bad
experience and I wanted to share a bit
of what that looked like for y'all. Let
me know how y'all feel and until next
time, let's just hope I don't knock any
cables out.
Peace, nerds.
Ah.